

# Charlotte Guertler, PhD

Mechanical Engineer Aerospace and Biomechanics

charlotteguertler.github.io

(id)

orcid: 0000-0003-0605-0239



LinkedIn: Charlotte Guertler



charlotte.guertler@gmail.com

#### About me ———

Charlotte is a mechanical engineer specializing in biomechanics and aerospace. She has experience in finite element analysis, mechanics, imaging, design, 3D bioprinting, material characterization, and project management. She is currently a mechanical engineering analyst at L3Harris. Previously, Charlotte was a Senior Scientist in brain biomechanics research and the associate director of the engineering design makerspace at Washington University and consulted for a neuroscience startup. Charlotte is excited to leverage her extensive analysis, research, design, and fabrication experience in R&D engineering.

#### Skills ———

R&D

Finite element analysis, animal/human studies, MR imaging, MR elastography (MRE), focused ultrasound

**Engineering Software** 

Femap, COMSOL, SolidWorks, Autodesk Fusion 360, Tinkercad

Building, fabrication, prototyping 3D printing, laser cutting, machining & fabrication, welding, woodworking, sandblasting & powder coating, injection molding, vacuum forming

**Publishing Software** 

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, CorelDRAW, Inkscape, LaTeX

## Education

2019 PhD Washington University in St. Louis

Mechanical Engineering & Materials Science Certificate in Imaging Science & Engineering

2017 MS Washington University in St. Louis

Mechanical Engineering & Materials Science

2014 BS Yale University

Mechanical Engineering, ABET accredited

### Research and Work Experience

2023-pres. Mechanical Engineering Analyst

L3Harris

Supervisors: Dave Calabrese and Kayla Mastovich

Finite element analysis of static, dynamic, and optical survival and per-

formance for the telescope of weather satellite pre-production.

2022 Engineering Consultant

RAPT Ventures, Inc.

Supervisor: Julia Whitehead

Product development of neuroscience-based infant language training

device.

2021-22 Senior Scientist

Washington University in St. Louis

Supervisor: Dr. Philip Bayly

Demonstrate immediate changes in brain mechanical properties postmortem using MRE and create 3D bioprinted hydrogels with tunable anisotropy. Responsibilities: conduct research, supervise PhD, masters, and undergraduates, manage projects, write publications and proposals

2021-22 Engineering Consultant

DeepSight Technology

Supervisor: John Chong

Design, prototype, and fabricate novel ultrasound phantoms, demos,

and experimental setups

2019-22 Associate Director

Spartan Light Metal Products Makerspace

Supervisor: Dr. Ruth J. Okamoto

Design and manage curriculum, vision, and operations for university-

wide makerspace

2019-21 Staff Research Scientist

Washington University in St. Louis

Supervisor: Dr. Philip Bayly

Develop novel anisotropic analysis for MR imaging of harmonic ultrasound-induced motion (MR-HUM) using machine learning and FEA and show effects of aging on anisotropy in brain using MRE.

2015-19 Graduate Student Researcher

Washington University in St. Louis

Supervisor: Dr. Philip Bayly

Demonstrate mechanical property differences between in vivo and ex vivo brain, develop novel imaging method: MR imaging of harmonic ultrasound-induced motion (MR-HUM), and investigate anisotropy using finite element analysis.

13 manuscripts in peer-reviewed journals

2 patents

## References

Philip V Bayly, PhD

The Lee Hunter Distinguished Professor of Mechanical Engineering

Chair, Mechanical Engineering & Materials Science

Washington University in St. Louis

pvb@wustl.edu; 314-935-6081

**Dave Calabrese** 

Senior Systems Engineer, Optical Payload Engineering

General Atomics

Previously: L3Harris Mechanical Engineering Manager

calabrese.dave@gmail.com; 508-930-6318